NEXT ENTERTAINMENT WORLD presents
a LEEYANG FILM & REAR WINDOW production
in association with VAST E&M
EXECUTIVE PRODUCER
KIM Woo-taek
PRODUCED BY
LEE hanseung, KIM Sung-hoon
HYUN Bin
JANG Dong-gun
I found it!
DIRECTED BY KIM Sung-hoon
Jemulpo
Got a wolf in your belly?
We got any meat? I'm thirsty!
Then drink the water!
Honey?
You okay?
RAMPANT
3 days earlier
Arquebus,
no need to wait for
the wick to burn out.
Light it and pull the trigger and bang!
Sieging the palace is a
child's play with this.
Gunpowder?
Give me 3-4 days.
Tomorrow midnight.
That's too soon.
Tomorrow night, I got no time too.
Captain!
Just kill me!
Hold out until tonight!
Who is that?
A man or a beast?
He's a man right now
but he could be a demon by tomorrow.
A demon?
We must depart in 2 days time.
Tell them, the deal is
good until tomorrow.
He wants to trade 600
guns with 37kg of silver.
That'll be enough to arm my men.
We'll wipe out the Qing soldiers
stationed here and move in...
Where's the ship?
It's docked near Jemulpo.
Get Baron Park.
Yes, sir.
Plotting an uprising from
the heart of the palace?
General?
Where did such a thing come from?
The Jemulpo rebels are
keeping their mouths shut.
They won't say where it's from,
and what their target is.
Damn you!
If this is a sign of an uprising,
I do not know how Qing
Emperor will react.
What do you advise?
It's an act of revolt
against you and this court.
We must find the perpetrators
and charge them with high treason.
Indeed.
This is a plot against me.
Initiate interrogation!
I'll oversee it myself!
General, I know where
your loyalty lies,
no need for any of this.
Who is behind this?
My desire to right the course
of this country is behind this.
Do your worst.
Is that so?
- General!
- Father!
Give this to Prince Ganglim.
I can't, Your Majesty.
The king will not stop.
You can't go, but if you must,
kill me first!
Sire, they are not the
traitors, please release them.
Return at once, this isn't your place.
Your Highness, they've armed
themselves with guns,
and conspired a revolt.
If that is not treason, then what is?
They desire to remove vile
Qing army and rebuild Joseon.
Shut your mouth!
I've told you many times
but you refused to listen.
Instead of the populace, you've
only listened to the eunuchs.
Shut your mouth!
If that is a conspiracy!
It is indeed!
Whether we submit to Ming or Qing,
it is a king's decision!
Whether this country prospers or
flounders, it is also my decision!
But you defied my will, how
is that not conspiracy?!
Then the one behind this plot...
is none other than me.
They were not the masterminds
behind this revolt,
but the Crown Prince of Joseon,
and your son Lee Young.
I will accept the capital punishment,
so I beg of you to stop
unnecessary bloodshed,
and release them at once.
Your Majesty!
Crown Prince!
I'll return soon! See you in Beijing!
There are plenty of beauties
in Joseon too, right?
Have some dignity as a prince!
You mustn't say stuff like
that within palace walls.
Bloody hell.
Profanity is used
only by the peasants,
how could you say that as
soon as we step on this land?
Please think before you speak...
And speak before you hit me!
We'll develop a beautiful
relationship by doing so...
Wait, why didn't anyone
come to greet me?
It's the prince, no less.
I'll give them hell.
Stupid idiots...
Look, was there a war?
Perhaps it was attacked
by the Japanese.
Go look around.
But you're the warrior, why me?
This way!
Do you know your way?
I'm new to Jemulpo.
This way is to the capital,
but where's the town office?
There isn't anyone
around to ask either,
not a damn soul.
No dogs or cats, not even a rat.
If so...
Look! There!
A plague?
But even so, must they
burn the corpses?
I've ordered a lockdown of Jemulpo,
and distribution of drawings
of the conspirators,
and give rewards to informants
and punish the accomplices.
You've ordered?
I've relayed your orders.
And?
Prince Ganglim will arrive
in Jemulpo today.
That bastard.
I'd have sent him a royal
order to return in time.
He never showed up for
any official functions,
but he'll be here at the first
news of his brother's death.
What holds in the future
for this country?
I did not become a king
to enjoy wealth and power,
and raise an ungrateful son.
Your Majesty, it is not your fault.
What I worry is, though,
with unsettling rumors
going around here,
I hope Ganglim's arrival
doesn't cause you to worry.
Unsettling rumors?
The Crown Princess found
a headless bird at the shrine.
It was the symbolic bird of your name.
The world conspires against me!
What did I do to deserve this?
Should I read your fortune?
Distress
Princess!
It's alright, my child.
Your mommy's here.
Prince, this is bad.
It's already dark, what do we do?
Find something to eat, I'm hungry.
Something to eat?
I'm hungry too.
I'm the one doing all the work,
wouldn't I be hungry too?
Hello? Is anyone here?
Anyone? Hello?
Can someone answer me?
Innkeeper!
Oh man, what the heck?
I'm on my way to the palace,
if you got any food to share...
Innkeeper!
I heard someone here.
Could you help?
Oh man, look at that...
Innkeeper?
Minister Kim, it's So-yong.
The princess is under house
arrest, as you wished.
His Highness ordered to not
feed her until she confesses,
so she won't last 3 days.
Good work.
Will it be okay?
She is pregnant, after all.
Pregnant with a traitor's seed.
What about Prince Ganglim?
We don't know the exact
reason for his return.
He won't return.
Pardon?
Bloody hell.
Not a single ant in sight,
let alone beauties.
Uprising at a time like this?
What? What is it?
Ghost! There's a ghost!
Like hell it is.
Royal guards! They must be it!
They're here!
We've been instructed to
escort you to the palace.
You're quite late.
My apologies, the message
arrived a moment ago.
Why bring so many to escort me back?
There is an uprising here...
Aren't you responsible for that?
One-eyed, hook hand, and big scars.
You're royal guards?
My Lord, we must leave
at once, there's a ghost...
Where's my horse? Didn't bring one?
Planned to leave without me?
My Lord!
Assassins? Ordered to kill and bury me?
Help!
Prince Ganglim!
What the...
Has she gone mad?
We must hurry, they got
a whiff of the blood.
Let's go.
Please!
What are you doing?
Why are you bringing him?
Please!
Why do you need him?
Who are you guys?
And what were those?
Be quiet, the demons are
sensitive to sound.
Demons?
Those things bit indiscriminately,
I could've...
What are you doing?!
He must be interrogated!
Please be quiet!
How dare you!
You're talking to Prince...
Prince Ganglim!
Yes, how did you know?
My Lord.
Come on, he's a prince.
How do you know me?
How did you know I'd go through here?
Are you also assassins
hired to kill me?
Or the traitors who
started the uprising?
Lower your sword.
We're neither assassins nor traitors.
We've been waiting for your return.
I was a servant of Crown Prince Lee.
Park Eul-ryong.
The one who delivered his message?
The demons rip humans'
flesh and drink the blood.
Pierce their hearts or heads
in order to kill them.
Their corpses must be burned.
Or they could come back to life.
What a load of shit.
So the burned corpse earlier
wasn't from a plague...
Its like a plague.
Those who are bitten by
them also turn into demons.
And they'll in turn attack others.
People are turning?
The demons were all
residents of this village.
These people's parents,
siblings, and children.
They may turn instantly
or later, but they all turn.
Where are the officials?
Because of the demons...
they've all fled in the
middle of the night.
The rest gathered here because
the demons are rampant at night.
Bloody hell...
Prince, save my mother,
please save her...
Dol-gae!
My Lord...
Your Highness...
They've been bitten by the demons.
The infection can be stopped
if it doesn't reach the heart.
They haven't turned, but
we're taking precautions.
Mother, please eat this.
Go on, you must eat to live.
Honey, I'm so thirsty...
Dol-gae...
I need meat...
Bring me some meat.
What was the capital's order?
They locked down Jemulpo.
No one can enter or leave.
They must be notified,
to get military support...
It's no use.
No one from the capital
will listen to us.
Save us, Crown Prince.
Stop!
What's with you?
I'm not the Crown Prince!
Crown Prince, save us...
Please save us...
Calm yourselves!
You'll become one when you
return to the palace.
What?
You're our last hope,
you can save us all.
Isn't that your brother's final wish?
Nope.
You got the wrong guy.
I can't be the Crown Prince
even if I wanted to.
So I'll never be your king.
- Prince...
- Enough!
You can't dictate who becomes
the Crown Prince, you traitors!
Bring this up again and
I'll lock you all up.
Your Highness!
Your Highness! Please save us!
Stand back!
Why did we hedge our bets
on someone like him?
May Buddha grace upon you.
It's rotten.
How much ration's left?
2 bags of potatoes and a
handful of barley, sir.
- Distribute equally.
- Yes, sir.
Beef jerky!
My Lord!
I should've taken some
food from the Qing ship.
There was so much food...
Qing fish cakes, Qing
crepes, Qing noodles,
- Qing dumplings...
- Qing booze...
Qing ladies...
How could you think of
them at a time like this?
You would too, if you ever had some.
Must you return to the palace?
The demons are one thing, but I
don't think you'll be welcomed.
Someone sent those assassins!
I have to, I must bring
Crown Princess to Qing.
What for?
Please think before you speak!
She's your brother's wife!
Even if you love the ladies so much,
that's a line you mustn't cross!
That's his will, he
wants her safe in Qing!
You should've said so...
Is he buried?
We were ambushed by these monsters...
Monsters?
It was a nightmare,
neither man nor beast...
I barely escaped, they got my men...
And the prince?
He's dead.
Are you sure?
I saw it with my own eyes.
The monsters tore him to pieces,
his blood splashed everywhere.
Could I get rest of my money, sir?
Were you bitten by those monsters?
Yes, so I beheaded it right away.
Follow me.
The money we agreed on
isn't enough, My Lord.
May I have some more
to help bury my men?
Open it.
Your silver is down there.
But I don't see anything...
My Lord! My Lord!
The demons must've taken over
Jemulpo, they'll be here soon,
is it still not the time?
Bring me So-yong.
Pardon?
Minister Kim? It's So-yong.
My apologies if I caused you to worry.
How could I ever doubt you?
Lord?
Is this the dawn of a new world?
What are you doing so
early in the morning?
Heading out to scrounge food.
What about the demons?
They can't stand the sun,
so they only move at night.
They hide in vacant
homes or in the forest.
Then why not just kill
them all during the day?
They could get us first at night.
You're a beauty under the sunlight.
Ever been to Qing?
No? Would you like to come?
Qing has more than enough
food and clothes for all.
How could you say that
at a time like this?
I'm mentioning it because of it.
To be honest, is this a country?
Why live in fear here?
Cold, hungry, so full of demons.
Ignorance is bliss.
What say you? I can take you to Qing.
You'll live a comfortable
life, just imagine.
Why bring up Qing when
my home is in chaos?
Are you a native of the Qing?
Dang, don't shout at me!
I'm as good as a Qing.
Although born in Joseon,
I was raised in Qing,
I speak better in Mandarin.
It's a shame that
you're a Joseon prince.
What?
- My Lord?
- You're worthless.
And Mandarin doesn't suit you.
That's impossible.
Did you just call me 'worthless'?
Yes, not worth your title.
Completely worthless.
- We got a problem!
- How dare you...
Your Highness! Please help!
Let's just head for the palace...
You're tiring me out...
Dol-gae!
Brother!
- Dol-gae!
- Deok-hee!
Dol-gae! My son!
Mother...
Honey...
Honey, no...
You must be in a great mood.
Your appetite is back and
your cheeks are rosy.
Perhaps due to last night's festivity.
I feel so energized with warm blood.
A fairy visited my bed in my dream.
Her pearly skin and silky
hair enveloped me!
A fairy in a dream is a good omen.
Is that so?
Not a fairy, it was me.
You were inside me.
You were so excited
to be between my legs...
What did she say?
I'll have the king's...
Crazy bitch, kill her! Kill her now!
I kept her by my side
and cared for her!
How dare she come after my life too?!
Kill them! Kill them all!
Kill every traitor in my palace!
You dressed so well by yourself!
Just look at that!
Prince Ganglim!
Upon your return, please send help.
We don't know how long we'll last.
It's not just Jemulpo.
The demons will chase blood of others,
and spread to the entire country.
I understand, I'll talk to the king.
We'll come with you.
Where? To the palace? For what?
I cannot trust you.
I want to see if you'll send the army.
I hope you don't shun the
peasants that die before you.
How dare you!
Even if it's daytime, it's
dangerous by yourself.
Allow us to escort you.
Very well, follow us.
But if I bring an army,
will you come to Qing with me?
Don't want to?
Fine, I'll go.
Just get through tonight.
The army will be here tomorrow.
Don't worry, Crown
Prince has promised us.
Promise? I didn't promise a thing.
The sun will set at this rate.
Let's get a move on.
Port Yanghwajin
I'm gatekeeper of Yanghwajin.
Prince Ganglim.
I know, My Lord, I escorted you to Qing.
You're really back.
You said you'd be back
to those sobbing ladies...
When did I?
In any case, bring me a boat.
Yes, My Lord.
However, they cannot cross the river.
Why not?
I've been ordered not to let
any Jemulpo peasants in.
So what exactly is the reason?
Demons are rampant in Jemulpo...
I guess you don't know yet,
but it's a long story.
Anyway, they're not infected,
so bring me the boat.
It's a royal order.
I'll get you another
one, get me the boat!
No, sire.
Then stop me.
I slept and ate with them,
I must be infected too!
My Lord!
I made a promise to them.
You're embarrassing
me in front of them.
They can't return to Jemulpo.
The demons will get to them
even before they reach Jemulpo.
Those demons are everywhere,
biting and sucking blood!
Don't believe me? Of course you don't.
I couldn't believe it either.
It's a royal order!
This guy's so uptight.
I don't believe it...
He's not worth it.
I must go alone, so wait here.
- Hak-su, you too.
- Pardon?
My Lord!
Be careful of the ministers.
They won't easily give you an army.
No need for these garbage,
I'll talk to the king directly.
They were the ones who sent assassins.
They also led Crown Prince
to his tragic demise.
What do you mean?
He didn't commit suicide?
It was an unavoidable decision.
To save the lives of his
followers and their families,
he offered his own life.
Who do you mean?
Minister of War Kim Ja-joon
and his 6 ministers.
Burn it.
Her eyes turned and teeth became sharp,
aren't those the same symptoms
as the Jemulpo plague?
This isn't the place
to discuss the plague.
The Qing envoy will arrive shortly,
make sure everything's in order.
But can sire receive
them with his injuries?
It's a royal message from the emperor.
It's his duty regardless of his health.
A messenger from
the west gate arrived.
Jemulpo peasants demanded that
they pass through Yanghwajin.
But aren't they infected
with the plague?
I do not know, but among them is
wanted rebel Park Eul-ryong.
But how...
They must be eliminated.
Ganglim is alive.
He arrived with them.
Any troubles on your journey?
I had many, sire.
Assassins made an attempt for my life,
and demons in Jemulpo
almost tore me to pieces.
Demons?
You don't know?
They're like beasts who
bite and drink human blood.
Their eyes gray and teeth sharp.
Anyone bitten turn into one of them.
How could you not know
about the chaos in Jemulpo?
I've heard that Jemulpo rebels
are spreading this rumor.
It is not a rumor!
Rebels cause civil unrest by
spreading vicious rumors.
I saw it with my own eyes!
It's an urgent matter.
They can easily reach
the capital in no time.
An army must be sent immediately
and wipe out the demons.
What say you, Minister Kim?
I'll dispatch a unit of reserves.
Minister of War?
Yes, My Lord.
So you're the puppet master,
head of this court.
Surprised to see me alive?
Your Highness, assign me an army.
I'll lead it myself to Jemulpo.
Very well, wipe out
the demons or rebels...
No, Your Majesty.
You dare to defy an
order from the king?
By the way, why have you come?
To claim the throne?
Is that why you came so
swiftly after Young's death?
I'd have sent a royal order in time.
"The king's heart is clouded
and his court polluted.
Please take my wife and
unborn child to Qing."
You ungrateful!
I came for the Crown Princess
as per his final wish.
I have no desire for the throne,
so please ease your mind.
The throne is forever yours.
As Joseon's king,
please live a long life.
Do you also blame me?
You also think I killed your brother?
He was my son, it tears me apart.
And I... I...
didn't...
do anything to him.
Get out of my sight.
Not doing anything is your crime.
Leave me.
We will...
overturn the world tonight.
My Lady, it's Ganglim.
A Qing merchant ship will
arrive tomorrow, be ready.
I've been dispatched to Jemulpo with...
I can't and won't go, it's all wrong.
This is his will.
He only thought of you
even in his final moments.
We must survive before
we can do anything else.
If I leave for Qing...
who will be able to console
his resentful spirit?
I can promise you one thing.
When I'm back from Jemulpo,
I'll avenge his death.
I'll leave a trail of their blood.
Ganglim.
My wish to rebuild Joseon
will be left unfulfilled.
The populace's sorrow deepens, but
the king's will cannot be changed.
All his good men are buried,
leaving only the corrupt by him.
If you were me, could you
have done differently?
Do me this favor.
Please take my wife and
unborn child to Qing.
What did I tell you?
I told you to come
live with me in Qing.
Leaving behind a beautiful wife
and a child, what a waste.
My Lord!
I told you to wait in Yanghwajin.
Park and his entourage
have been arrested!
What?
They turned out to be outlaw rebels!
I told you, we shouldn't
have mingled with them.
The king retracted his military order.
Why have you taken Jemulpo
peasants into custody?
Do you not know?
Park and his cohorts are rebels
who started an uprising.
He's a rebel for protecting
the people from demons?
Demons?
There aren't any, it must be rabies.
Of course there are, there's
plenty right here too.
How are you any different from demons?
Prince! Even if you're
the heir to the throne,
how could you accuse the ministers?
You'll take responsibility
for your words!
What a load of horseshit...
What did he say?
Prince!
Qing envoy will be here soon.
Crown Princess was
ordered to participate.
Ministers, please get ready.
You will attend, won't you?
Do not think that you'll
have your way again.
I am not like my brother.
He had things to protect, but not me.
Why have you returned?
You didn't want anything to
do with Joseon, then why?
It's not too late, walk away quietly.
Then I'll let you keep your head.
He'd like you to know.
There was an incident
yesterday morning.
A royal concubine with
rabies bit His Highness,
and his eyes turned red
and his skin pale since then.
Minister is worried that His
Highness may be infected.
King Lee of Joseon.
Your last tribute was insultingly poor.
Have you forgotten your pledge?
I will generously allow another
chance to send a tribute.
Where's the court physician?
Court physician! Where are you?!
I heard you treated sire, how is he?
The woman must've been infected,
she went berserk during breakfast
and attacked the king...
Was he bitten?
Yes.
I've used orpiment and
his condition improved.
My Lord! Where are you going?!
To the party!
But it's late, the sun is about to set!
Wait for me!
You wait here.
My Lord! Wait!
This is a talisman made
by a fortune teller.
I'm okay, you keep it.
My Lord, please!
This will protect you from evil,
keep this with you.
As you promised, bring
back just Crown Princess.
It is a joyous day,
I'd like to recite a poetry
to commemorate this occasion.
The mountain is dark,
and no moon in sight,
leaves have fallen,
and so did the first frost.
Where will you go in this night,
a dog barks in a quaint village.
Sire would like us to
drink to our guests,
please fill your glasses.
Cheers!
Sire!
Your Highness!
Father...
What have you done, Minister?!
He was infected with the plague
and turned into a demon.
I'm sure you've all
heard of the demons.
Tell us, Prince Ganglim.
You know more about the
demons than anyone here.
Is this a demon or a man?
The Emperor will not condone
what happened here today!
Go tell the Emperor!
Minister!
Joseon of yesterday is finished.
The New Joseon that I'll erect
will not be slave to Qing!
Please hurry, this way!
Are you alright?
Hold onto me, do not let go.
Okay.
My Lord! Here!
Get to the lockup!
Yes, sir!
Let me talk to Prince Ganglim,
then I'll tell you everything.
Continue!
Stop!
Your Highness.
The palace is overrun with demons!
My Lord! The demons!
I'm sure you've heard
rumors about demons,
they're all true.
He is not a man, but a demon.
Gather all royal guards in the palace.
If we do not stop them,
the palace is finished.
But without a royal order...
The king is dead.
Sire, the gates must be secured first.
If they leave the palace,
the capital will fall!
Dispatch the royal guards
around palace walls!
Not one demon can leave the palace!
Yes, sir!
- Where's everyone?
- They're locked up.
Quick, close the gates!
Those demons...
It's the plague...
- Cover the door.
- Yes, sir!
This way.
Free everyone.
Brother!
- Is everyone okay?
- Yes.
Quickly free everyone.
Yes, sir!
This is Park Hyun, I trained with him.
He can be trusted.
Please kill me, sir...
Maintain formation!
The demons mustn't leave the palace!
- Understand?!
- Yes, sir!
This all started because of
a foreign merchant ship.
I told Minister of War about the ship.
He was threatening my family's life...
No, he's the devil,
he must be beheaded.
What did he say?
He must be killed before
a disaster arrives.
Do you mean Kim Ja-joon knew about it?
The ship and the demons?
It's all over.
And this is the beginning.
It doesn't matter if there
are thousands of them.
We have enough guns and gunpowder,
we'll get the reserves to
wipe them out upon sunrise.
Everyone's dead, the king
and the royal blood!
Who should spearhead a new country?
Do you mean a revolution?
But that's treason.
No, dawn of a new world.
This country doesn't belong
to King Lee's lineage.
You've all talked about a new world.
Without any change, Joseon will fall,
but with the same lineage
in place, what can change?
But now is the time.
With the country in ruins,
I will raise a new country,
and you'll all become
its founding ministers.
Prince Ganglim could still be alive.
Joseon's heritage can only be
carried on by his lineage!
- Minister!
- My Lord!
I did not ask you about right and wrong.
That's up to me to decide now.
Make up your mind.
Will you join me,
or get buried with the king?
Defend the left flank!
The inner gate! Protect the inner gate!
Do not fall back!
Anyone retreating will be punished!
My Lord!
Help!
Hak-su, hurry! Over here!
This door won't hold!
Hurry!
Open the window!
Yes, sir!
Out of the way, tie
this to either ends!
Hurry!
Get out!
Brother!
Hurry, Prince!
- My Lord!
- Park!
Are you alright?
Finally, a new world.
The 200 royal guards likely
fought off the demon wave.
Rest of the demons can
be killed in the day.
Go to Yanghwajin and
bring back the reserves.
As you wish, Minister Kim.
I mean, Your Highness.
Scour the palace and find
Ganglim and Crown Princess.
He's tenacious, he'll be alive.
Who else was bitten?
Minister...
Your hand...
Minister, we better start another
talk about the new world.
About who will take the throne.
Wait.
The infection can be
stopped if I cut my arm...
Calm down, you're being stubborn.
You'll die anyway.
Minister.
In the next life...
do not be born as a king.
Have you found Kim?
Not yet...
He couldn't have survived last night.
He's either dead or
turned into a demon.
Find him, whether as
a body or a demon.
There were about
500 demons last night.
Even more will attack
the palace tonight.
You must call the reserves.
Please kill me.
You're the only one who can
mobilize the reserves.
Get to Yanghwajin and bring them.
Rest of you, protect
him to Yanghwajin.
If he turns before then,
kill him at once.
They'll believe you if they
see a demon in the flesh.
Will you accept this mission?
Yes, sir.
Prince Ganglim.
Reaching Yahghwajin
is not the problem.
The reserves cannot
reach here by sunset.
Gather the survivors, we'll
leave the palace at once.
If the demons climb these walls,
it's all over for Joseon.
Then that is Joseon's fate.
Is there another way?
I cannot leave, no, I won't leave.
Princess...
Must we abandon here
to save ourselves?
How are you any different
than the last king?
I am not a king.
Crown Prince wouldn't do this.
He's dead!
I'm not asking you to take the throne!
Just save the innocent people...
Find a way, that is your duty.
Will you come to Qing once
demons are dealt with?
So the guns were moved here?
Yes.
Then the fire tactic
is the only option.
We lure the demons to
one spot and light a fire.
Park, move the drum
to the royal villa.
- Hurry!
- Yes, sir!
Monk, gather and plant
dry branches and resins.
The rest of you, gather oil pots
and spray around the villa.
Make it very flammable.
Also, lock all doors so
that demons can't escape,
and make the walls flammable as well.
As many demons must be held here.
I created this new world...
Do not forget...
I am the king of New Joseon.
Over here.
Keep an eye out here.
Sir, where's the talisman?
Be careful.
Gather the gunpowders.
I'll check inside too.
I'll take that.
Monk!
Oh no...
My Lord!
Park Hyun!
Go upstairs!
Get out!
You go first!
- Prince! My Lord!
- My Lord! Hurry!
- Sire!
- Go!
My Lord! Hurry!
Hak-su, get out! Now!
My Lord! Please hurry!
My Lord.
My Lord!
Where's Hak-su?
Sire!
- Prince Ganglim!
- Hak-su!
My Lord, just go...
No, Prince Ganglim! It's too late.
Always think before you act...
Don't... lose the talisman...
Watch out for... dog
shit on the street...
Hak-su, no...
My Lord...
Hak-su! Hak-su!
Hak-su! No!
It's getting dark, we must hurry.
- This is the last batch!
- Take it outside.
Princess, get away!
Get the gunpowder inside!
- Man-bo!
- You okay?
Man-bo!
Go inside, this is as far as I can go.
I cannot go inside...
Please hurry!
Crown Princess!
- Hurry!
- Bring her inside.
I want to...
die as a man...
Do me this favor, monk.
No... please...
Man-bo, do not...
reincarnate into this world.
May Buddha grace upon you.
Man-bo... no...
The sun will set soon.
It's almost time.
Take Crown Princess
and leave the palace.
I'll leave behind to light the fire.
I'll stay back.
No, I'll stay.
You all leave now.
I'm staying.
Escort Crown Princess to Yanghwajin.
No, My Lord. You must stay alive.
I don't plan on dying.
I'll light the fire and join you.
After burning these demons.
I was bitten during the skirmish.
It's near the heart, so
I'll start turning shortly.
Bloody hell...
May Buddha grace upon you.
I should be able to hold out
until I light the fire.
Brother...
It's okay, Deok-hee, we all die once.
Will you leave for Qing?
I hope you come back.
Rebuild this palace and
Joseon when you do.
I said I don't want to!
You kept saying that,
but got here this far.
I didn't come here to be a king.
I came to bring back
you pitiful souls.
No one took pity on us.
No one tried to save us.
No one ever heard our cries.
But you did.
Isn't that the duty of the king?
Now that I've met the king,
I can die peacefully.
Shit...
Brother...
Everyone out.
I'll bang the drum in 15 minutes.
Prince!
Sire!
Where are you going?
Princess, go on ahead.
I'll light the villa and come back.
But My Lord...
I will go.
This is my duty.
And you.
Don't wait for anyone,
no one will come to save you.
You must save yourselves.
Save this country and
choose your king.
Bloody hell... So many...
Come back, Crown Prince.
A king must exist before people...
Excuse me.
Deok-hee!
Dammit!
Let's end this.
Joseon is finished.
Die, son of a perished country.
Aim!
Fire!
Park,
do you see?
It's the people.
The king before the people?
You're wrong.
People must exist
for the king to exist.
I'm sorry to be late.
Where are you, father...
Dol-gae.
Look! It's the Crown Prince!
He's coming!